{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Web Systems and Technologies",
    "Term": "Prelims",
    "Title": "01 Handout 1 - INTRODUCTION TO HTML",
    "LastModified": "18 February 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "01 Handout 1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the standard markup language for creating web pages?",
      "answer": "HyperText Markup Language",
      "choices": [
        "Hypermedia Text Markup Language",
        "Hyper Transferable Markup Language",
        "HyperText Manipulation Language",
        "HyperText Markup Language"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What allows web authors to arrange and define how content should be displayed?",
      "answer": "HyperText Markup Language",
      "choices": [
        "Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)",
        "JavaScript",
        "Python",
        "HyperText Markup Language"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to how links on the web let users move from one document to another?",
      "answer": "HyperText",
      "choices": [
        "Hypermedia",
        "Hyper Transfer",
        "Hyper Transmission",
        "HyperText"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the fifth and latest version of the language that supports multimedia?",
      "answer": "HTML5",
      "choices": [
        "HTML4",
        "XHTML",
        "HTML3",
        "HTML5"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what year was HTML introduced?",
      "answer": 1993,
      "choices": [
        1990,
        1995,
        1998,
        1993
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What organization manages the specifications of HTML?",
      "answer": "World Wide Web Consortium",
      "choices": [
        "International Organization for Standardization",
        "Internet Engineering Task Force",
        "Web Hypertext Application Technology Working Group",
        "World Wide Web Consortium"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of file is created in a text editor, containing elements, attributes, and tags?",
      "answer": "HTML Document",
      "choices": [
        "CSS Stylesheet",
        "JavaScript File",
        "Python Script",
        "HTML Document"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the naming conventions in an HTML document that tell the computer and web browser it is in HTML?",
      "answer": "html, head, title, and body",
      "choices": [
        "header, footer, section, and article",
        "div, span, p, and img",
        "table, tr, td, and th",
        "html, head, title, and body"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What file extension is required for saving an HTML document?",
      "answer": ".html",
      "choices": [
        ".htm",
        ".txt",
        ".css",
        ".html"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the component of an HTML document containing formats, instructions, and semantic meaning?",
      "answer": "HTML Element",
      "choices": [
        "HTML Attribute",
        "HTML Tag",
        "HTML Document",
        "HTML Element"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the basic unit of text in an HTML document?",
      "answer": "Paragraph",
      "choices": [
        "Heading",
        "List",
        "Image",
        "Paragraph"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What element is used to add a line break to the HTML code?",
      "answer": "br",
      "choices": [
        "p",
        "div",
        "span",
        "br"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What element is used to make text bold?",
      "answer": "strong",
      "choices": [
        "p",
        "em",
        "div",
        "strong"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is used to modify or define an HTML element?",
      "answer": "HTML Attribute",
      "choices": [
        "HTML Element",
        "HTML Tag",
        "HTML Document",
        "HTML Attribute"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another term for an HTML attribute?",
      "answer": "name=value pair",
      "choices": [
        "key-value pair",
        "property-value pair",
        "attribute-value pair",
        "name=value pair"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What defines how web browsers will format and display the content on an HTML file?",
      "answer": "HTML Tags",
      "choices": [
        "HTML Attributes",
        "HTML Elements",
        "HTML Documents",
        "HTML Tags"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are titles or subtitles that can be displayed on a webpage?",
      "answer": "Headings",
      "choices": [
        "Paragraphs",
        "Lists",
        "Images",
        "Headings"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many levels of headings are there in HTML?",
      "answer": "six levels",
      "choices": [
        "four levels",
        "five levels",
        "seven levels",
        "six levels"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What provides a way to navigate between webpages?",
      "answer": "Links",
      "choices": [
        "Forms",
        "Tables",
        "Images",
        "Links"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an alternative way to interact with the server and collect user inputs?",
      "answer": "Form",
      "choices": [
        "Table",
        "List",
        "Image",
        "Form"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What allows web developers to organize and arrange data into rows and columns?",
      "answer": "HTML Table",
      "choices": [
        "HTML Form",
        "HTML List",
        "HTML Division",
        "HTML Table"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What tag is used to create a table?",
      "answer": "table tag",
      "choices": [
        "form tag",
        "div tag",
        "list tag",
        "table tag"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of URL directs to another website?",
      "answer": "absolute URL",
      "choices": [
        "relative URL",
        "local URL",
        "global URL",
        "absolute URL"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of URL directs to a file within the same website?",
      "answer": "relative URL",
      "choices": [
        "absolute URL",
        "local URL",
        "global URL",
        "relative URL"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the top row of a table that acts as a title for the type of information in each column?",
      "answer": "Table Header",
      "choices": [
        "Table Footer",
        "Table Body",
        "Table Row",
        "Table Header"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What indicates the number of rows displayed in a table?",
      "answer": "Table Row",
      "choices": [
        "Table Header",
        "Table Data",
        "Table Footer",
        "Table Row"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What holds the data displayed in a table?",
      "answer": "Table Data",
      "choices": [
        "Table Header",
        "Table Row",
        "Table Footer",
        "Table Data"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is used to join two or more columns in a table?",
      "answer": "Colspan",
      "choices": [
        "Rowspan",
        "Cellspan",
        "Tablespan",
        "Colspan"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is used to join two or more rows in a table?",
      "answer": "Rowspan",
      "choices": [
        "Colspan",
        "Cellspan",
        "Tablespan",
        "Rowspan"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What attribute is used to separate table cells?",
      "answer": "Border",
      "choices": [
        "Spacing",
        "Padding",
        "Margin",
        "Border"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What tags are used to group the header, footer, and body content in a table?",
      "answer": "thead, tfoot, and tbody",
      "choices": [
        "header, footer, and body",
        "top, bottom, and middle",
        "start, end, and center",
        "thead, tfoot, and tbody"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the short for Document Type Definition?",
      "answer": "!DOCTYPE",
      "choices": [
        "!HTML",
        "!DOCUMENT",
        "!WEBPAGE",
        "!DOCTYPE"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is referred to as the \"root element\" of an HTML document?",
      "answer": "html",
      "choices": [
        "head",
        "body",
        "title",
        "html"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What element shows extra information about an HTML document?",
      "answer": "title",
      "choices": [
        "head",
        "body",
        "meta",
        "title"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the container for metadata in an HTML document?",
      "answer": "head",
      "choices": [
        "html",
        "body",
        "title",
        "head"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is placed between the html and the body tags?",
      "answer": "head",
      "choices": [
        "footer",
        "body",
        "title",
        "head"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is used to specify page description, author, and character coding?",
      "answer": "meta",
      "choices": [
        "head",
        "title",
        "body",
        "meta"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What defines the content of an HTML document displayed in the browser?",
      "answer": "body",
      "choices": [
        "head",
        "html",
        "title",
        "body"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What defines the connection between the current document and an external source?",
      "answer": "link",
      "choices": [
        "script",
        "a",
        "src",
        "link"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is used to embed a client-side script?",
      "answer": "script",
      "choices": [
        "link",
        "style",
        "a",
        "script"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What attribute points to an external script file?",
      "answer": "src",
      "choices": [
        "href",
        "link",
        "script",
        "src"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a data about data?",
      "answer": "metadata",
      "choices": [
        "datadata",
        "meta",
        "data",
        "metadata"
      ],
      "reference": "01 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelims"
    }
  ]
}